# **LESLEY SABLATURA**

lesleysab210@gmail.com 713.855.3057 thelesleysab.com linkedin.com/in/lesleysab

# **Objective**

After spending 5+ years as a product owner and product manager for several enterprise software companies, my passion for problem-solving and creating delightful products led me to the desire to fix and create with my own hands. I want to continue my front-end software development experience in the Denver market to further fuel my tenacity for learning and creating.

#### **Technical Skills**

Front End: JavaScriptES6 | React | HTML| CSS | RESTful API | Redux | Socket.io | Material UI | React-Md

**Back End:** Node | Express | MongoDB | Mongoose

Other: Git | Node | SQL | JIRA | Agile

# **Professional Experience**

**DIGITAL PHARMACIST** | Software Engineer | Austin, TX | 2019 - present

Digital Pharmacist helps local pharmacies attract more patients. While working as a front-end developer, I work on a new product offering secure chat capability between patients and pharmacists (Inbox). My core activities include:

- Create new features and functionality on the Inbox product using React, Redux and Material UI.
- Create modular, responsive templates using CSS techniques and JavaScript libraries.
- Ensure delightful usability, responsiveness, and meet 508 accessibility compliance during the development process.
- Recommend solutions for a streamlined, user-friendly interface with the product and design team.

#### **KEET HEALTH** | Product Manager | Austin, TX | 2018 - 2019

- Performed regression, user acceptance testing and cross-browser testing; write acceptance criteria.
- Lead design and launch efforts for new product in existing application, Keet Outcomes; plus a new version of the product written in React, Ruby on Rails.
- Assisted with Tier 2 support; write SQL queries to troubleshoot and define bugs for development
- Created wireframes using Sketch to assist front end developers.
- Collaborated with Engineering, Operations, Finance and Marketing teams to improve release and launch planning.
- Conducted user research through in-person and virtual research sessions and translated those insights into feature changes to improve product engagement.

#### **TAVHEALTH** | Product Manager | Austin, TX | 2016-2018

- Performed regression and user acceptance testing; wrote acceptance testing criteria.
- Defined product requirements, launch plan and deadlines for a Groovy on Grails application that addressed social determinants of health where patient privacy laws (HIPAA and state privacy laws) were at the center of the product.
- Assisted with Tier 2 support by identifying and defining bugs for development team.
- Collaborated with Engineering and Operations teams to improve release process and increased response time to production incidences.
- Defined UX design along with UX and front end developers to ensure delightful usability, responsiveness, and to meet 508 accessibility compliance.
- Provided input into style-guide written with atomic design.
- JIRA ninja. Created, managed, prioritized, documented all business and some technical requirements and documentation in Atlassian suite.
- Conducted user research through in-person and virtual research sessions and translated those market insights into feature changes to improve product engagement.

### **BUZZ POINTS** | Product Manager | Austin, TX | 2015-2016

- Performed regression and user acceptance testing; wrote acceptance criteria.
- JIRA ninja. Created, managed, prioritized, documented all business and some technical requirements and documentation in Atlassian suite.

- Launched new product, Buzz Insight by using customer insights and metrics to drive product development.
- Oversaw sprint planning, measured velocity, set the deployment vision along with lead developer, developed the launch strategy, and successfully deployed beta product.

## MCKESSON | Product Owner | The Woodlands, TX | 2008 - 2015

Previous roles: PHYSICIAN PRACTICE MANAGER & SENIOR PHYSICIAN LIAISON

- Used SAP Business Objects to build data visualization capabilities for an analytics platform designed for physician liaisons. Designed the product visualization and drove the product roadmap to help scale the business at the physician, practice, and network levels.
- Prioritized the sequences of the backlog according to business value and ROI. Logged user stories and software bugs.
- Defined and prioritized user stories, triaged bugs, and managed the product backlog. Participated in daily scrums, sprint planning meetings, sprint reviews, and retrospectives.

### **SALIX PHARMACEUTICALS** | Sales Representative | Dallas, TX | 2007 - 2008

- Sold four gastroenterology products by prospecting, penetrating, and creating new relationships with clients.
- Delivered the highest level of sales and customer service on behalf of Salix through sales presentations, marketing materials, and sales techniques.

### BAYER HEALTHCARE | Diabetes Sales Specialist | San Antonio, TX | 2004 - 2007

Previous role: RETAIL SALES REPRESENTATIVE

- Promoted Bayer's premiere line of diabetes products and drove deals to closure with hospital systems, physicians, and retail pharmacists.
- Ranked #3 in the nation out of 175 Diabetes Sales Specialists in 2006-2007 fiscal year.
- Ranked #1 in the nation out of 40 Retail Sales Specialists in 2005.

### **Education**

**AUSTIN CODING ACADEMY** | Full Stack JavaScript Developer Program | 2018 **TEXAS WOMAN'S UNIVERSITY** | Masters of Business Administration | 2013 **TEXAS A&M UNIVERSITY** | Bachelors of Arts Journalism | 2002

#### **Professional Certifications**

- Certified Scrum Master (CSM)
- Certified Scrum Product Owner (CSPO)

# **Personal Projects**

**BIDRRR** | <a href="https://github.com/lesleysab/bidr">https://github.com/lesleysab/bidr</a> | React, Mongoose, MongoDB, Node.js, Express Bidding application that allows event-goers to bid on dog houses for Barkitecture ATX organization.

- Integrated with database to render components with data and to allow the creation of new components.
- Designed front end with Material UI with React to create an intuitive and minimal design to enhance the user experience.

**WEATHER FINDR** | <a href="https://github.com/lesleysab/reactflask">https://github.com/lesleysab/reactflask</a> | Python Flask, React, Bootstrap Find out the temperature and conditions in any city in the world.

- Integrated with free weather API.
- Connected server using Python Flask.
- Designed front-end with React and React Bootstrap.

**BARKITECTURE ATX** | <a href="https://github.com/lesleysab/bark-new">https://github.com/lesleysab/bark-new</a> | React, Materialize, React Image Gallery Production site that provides event information for local non-profit organization that brings local builders, architects and designers together to design dog houses to compete and auction off at annual event.

- Leveraged Materialize for design and React Image Gallery for displaying images.
- Designed front end and multiple views in React and React Router.
- Collaborated with the organization's leaders to ensure sign off on design and timeline